Oliver Payne

66 Forest Glade Highams Park London E4 9RH

Tel: 07806935465

Email: orpayne@btinternet.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oliver-payne-56038a157
Youtube Channel: https://www.youtube.com/c/olliepaynemusic

Profile

Creative, proactive and hard-working individual, with over 3 years of experience in AV Advertising. Enjoys the problem-solving aspects of the role. Polite and professional communication with team members and clients within a dynamic and flexible environment. Organised and detail conscious; can be relied upon to complete any task to a high standard.

Employment and Experience

The Specialist Works - Senior AV Executive (Angel, London N1)

2023 - 2024

- Responsible for the AV Planning & Buying across a range of UK and International clients (Autotrader, Frasers Group (Sports Direct, Game, Jack Wills, Flannels, Under Armour), Betfred, Mejuri, Eharmony, Balsam Hill, Abel&Cole and others)
- Presented AV plans and PCA's to clients in both F2F & Online settings, involving individual AV plans which amounted to £2 million & PCA's for new clients to the business
- Complimented by senior staff members as being a valuable member of the team and can be counted upon when tasks need to be completed quickly and to a high standard
- Line manager to one of the Junior AV Executives, ensuring that they have the training available to build their knowledge, as well as providing support and guidance
- Led training sessions in DDS, Caria, Concept, Dashboards/Frontsheets for colleagues at a junior level within the business

The Specialist Works - AV Executive (Angel, London N1)

2021 - 2023

- In charge of successfully buying AV campaigns for clients, including one which amounted to £3 million across 2 months
- Built strong relationships with Saleshouses (ITV, Channel 4, Sky, Eurosport, Virgin Media) over phone calls & emails, helping to boost efficiency for our AV campaigns
- Highly experienced with the following platforms/tools: DDS, Techedge, Microsoft (Excel, Powerpoint & Word), Caria (Buying & Creative), Mint AV, Adalyser, Ad Intel, TV Squared, Planet V, C4 Portal, Sky Analytics, Concept
- Set up social nights for the team to help build strong relationships

Publicis Media - Investment Executive (Chancery Lane, London WC2) 2020 - 2021

- Sole responsibility for the promotion of P&G products on ITV (Scotland and Northern Ireland), Channel 4, Talking Pictures and Eurosport, maintaining a high peak percentage with great quality for each TV spot.
- Experience advertising on digital platforms for the Haircare brands within P&G
- Skilled with platforms/tools such as: Mediaocean, Flashtalking, MOAT, Nielsen, Jira, Telmar

Publicis Media - Paid Search Executive (Chancery Lane, London WC2) 2019 - 2020

- Daily advertising for P&G products through multiple search engines (Google, Bing, Amazon), ensuring client objectives were met across all campaigns.
- Involved in processes such as keyword selection, ad copy creation, Google Ads quality checking
- Experienced with platforms/tools such as: Google Adwords, Google Analytics, Google Trends, Google Data Studio, Amazon Advertising, Criteo, Microsoft Teams and Microsoft Outlook.

Copper Brown Record Label - Sound Engineer/Producer

2017 - 2019

- Assisted in Producing, Recording, Mixing, and Mastering processes
- Recorded artists such as Poppy Ackroyd, The London African Gospel Choir, Stella Angelika, The Boondock Hippy and Justin Schlosberg
- Worked with industry-standard equipment such as: Logic Pro X, Universal Audio,
 Waves, Slate Digital, Neve, Neumann, Sennheiser, Shure, Coles

Training & Education

TV Masters - Pass (Thinkbox)	2021
Digital Marketing Level 3 - Pass (Whitehat GB, now known as Multiverse)	2020
Principles of Marketing - Pass (British Computer Society)	2019
Principles of Coding - Pass (British Computer Society)	2019
Fundamentals of Digital Marketing - Pass (Google Digital Garage)	2019
Sound Engineering Extended Diploma - Merit (Access to Music)	2018
AS level grades:	2016
- Mathematics E, Physics E	
GCSE grades:	2015
- 12 GCSE's	

Hobbies & Interests

I like to record/produce music covers and original songs for my YouTube channel, performing these songs in live events when possible. I enjoy running and swimming, training around 2-3 times weekly. My interest in swimming has come from a young age, when I swam for a club and partook in monthly competitions to test my ability.